when i was a student uh at columbia
one day i was accidentally brought
into a lecture
uh
by somebody
whose name that sounds very strange to
me it was the first couple years as i
arrived in america
english wasn't quite there
the name sounds like a free lunch buffet
but that lecture
buff buffett really fundamentally uh
changed the correct true director of my
life in america and really give the
career that i enjoyed immensely today
and so it gave me a great pleasure to be
back into this title of the setting to
communicate directly with the student
and today i want to talk a little bit
about some of the
value investing
the basic concept of values
investing obviously is
many many decades old but today i think
it is as relevant
as
when it was first laid out by benjamin
graham
and columbia
six seven decades ago
and essentially just the three basic
ideas
the first one is the stock is not a
piece of paper that you treat but it
represents fractional ownership of a
company
and therefore evaluating the stock
ought to really have a basic barriers
of evaluating the company as a whole
and then secondly that you value in any
financial asset
that
you have to really predict in the future
the discounted cash flow of the future
cash earnings
and the future is inherently
difficult
to predict
and
therefore you really want to leave
yourself a margin of safety
so that you could be wrong
or you could be right but because the
future is a distribution of
opportunity i mean statistic
possibilities
say you bet on something that ninety
percent of the chances you could be
right
but then the ten percent chance occurred
so
all of a sudden become a hundred percent
so you want to leave enough a margin of
safety in other words you want to buy
the low enough of a price
even if all the adverse
events occurred against you in the
future
you will still be in the game it doesn't
mean you won't lose money but it just
means that you not lose so much that
you'll be out of the game because
investing is really a long game
it complains over the life of anybody's
career
and so you want to be really in the game
somehow over the long haul
and the third concept is mr market
to figure out a frame of mind to think
that
when the market is against you
you look at it as a
a neurotic
uh
mr market that's prone for emotional and
irrational behaviors
so those are the three basic concepts at
the heart of it is obviously it is this
bargain idea that you want to really get
what you pay for
now
obviously that's what everybody wanted
and if everybody want the same thing you
would think that
all of the professional investors will
be value investors
and that's just the further
thing from truth
in fact value investing is properly
practiced constitutes a tiny small
minority of all the investment
professionals
majority of the people hold a different
views
and let me just articulate for them the
alternative view of providing investing
number one
yes stock
legally represents fractional claims of
fractional ownership
but is first and foremost a piece of a
paper you can treat all the time
and therefore it follows that successful
investing lies in the successful
guessing
of the stock movement
based on whatever informed theories or
practices
that you can find
and thirdly
that the market is to be respected
indeed to be feared
because they really through the market
you can actually find a value and
through the market you can actually buy
and
sell
so this scenario ago a different view
and it sounds even more persuasive
than the first reviews that i laid out
as a value investor
in fact i would say majority of the
people when you follow the ladder rather
than the formal
so as a young student trying to get into
the business which way do you follow
i would suggest that before you do that
you will go through some fundamental
studies as to the result
of there is a different approach and
philosophies
unfortunately there has been numerous
studies
have done because
we kept a pretty good track record uh
over the last 100 years that we used to
visit
and and all the studies that have
given a mistaken conclusion
that the true value of investors as a
practiced
have consistently uh
outperformed the market whereas all just
about all other strategies
either match the market or
severely underperform the market over a
long period of time
now you can dispute the result of it but
i think the evidence is pretty
persuasive
and so the question becomes if that were
the case
of course the study also concluded that
the
true value investors that is a properly
practiced really are a tiny small
percentage
of investing
professionals that is also a very
interesting study and but they really do
conform
our day-to-day observation having been
in this profession for close to 20 years
so why is the case why is the case
if the
empirical studies conclude
overwhelmingly
that going through the value investing
is is the way to go
and
the philosophies of the practice are
being well articulated for seven decades
and well practiced and
publicized by
tremendous successful examples such as
mr buffett as we just mentioned
why not more people follow what they do
what it turn out has a lot to do with
human psychology
in manual investing
you have to have this
frame of mind that
if you did your work correctly or the
market against you
you should be comfortable standing alone
and this is the concept behind mr market
but that's really very difficult to do
it is a very
unnatural thing to do
when the whole market is against you
when everybody else you really think
you're stupid
and uh erotic and wrong
and you now tend to think everybody else
isn't mr marketing rational neurotic
uh that is very very unnatural things to
do and was
the borderlines of the self delusion
indeed that's probably most people's
view about you at the time
you look quite ridiculous and very
uncomfortable
in fact our very
evolution requires a certain deal of
conformity
think about over the millennials over
the uh millions of years of evolutionary
past
our ancestors our animal predecessors uh
you know basically hunting groups
and if one was left out and disagree
with everybody else in the group
very easily that one is not the one to
survive
so all the genes that have survived in
the past are the ones content to
extreme degree of conformity
and conformity
also works very well as
for human society because we are
at the end at the heart of social
animals
we need in that
sense of glue of a conformity and the
sympathy
compassion to bring the society in peace
and live together
so you need a certain mutated genes in a
sense to be utterly comfortable to stand
alone when everybody else disagree with
you
now that is the reason at least that's
one of the reasons the financial market
in itself is not that efficient
free market ever since it was practiced
a lot in time about two three hundred
years ago
has worked remarkably well
but it's worked most
remarkably well primarily i think
goods and services
physical goods and definable services
we have several hundred years of
overwhelming evidence to support that
but every country
practice that one all turn out to be
extraordinarily prosperous
now we also have a several hundred years
of history
a free market is a practice in the
financial market they're full of
disasters
up and down and tree movement
it doesn't really work nearly as well
when it comes to financial assets
why is it
well the financial asset at the core in
essence
is a discounted mechanism
to predict the future
it's the discounted estimated
cash earnings into the infinity
and of course we all know a we cannot
predict infinity would be we can't even
predict
immediately beyond what we can see which
is usually very short
and so there's a necessary element of a
speculation and guessing estimation
into the valuations of financial asset
when that is exaggerated there is an
element in stock market and the
financial market in general the element
of a gambling
element of a guessing element of a
speculation
and as we all know in pure casinos and
pure gambling
there is a huge advantage stock against
players
and really to the benefit of a casino
owners who define their news
this is why gambling is such a
profitable
business
and yet that has never really
persuaded the people away from gambling
there is certain element
uh that really fit human nation and love
gamble
even if everybody knows the oz is
stacked against
that has never protected
prevented gambling from a very big
business especially when it's allowed
ascension by the government
such as a practice in nevada or macau in
certain different geographies around the
world
and so there is some aspect of that one
in the financial market as well and this
is the reason why
that
it does not work
perfectly well as recently illustrated
by the
2008-2009
financial crisis which is only in the
stream of a long history of financial
crisis
but it doesn't really mean
that we have a better way of dealing
with that
so it's just as the churchill said about
democracy is perhaps the worst except
when comparison all the others
and so is the market
so it's the free market
when it comes to financial assets
it doesn't work very well
attorney doesn't work nearly as well as
goods and services
but it's still
one of the better ways we have come up
with
in terms of the facilitating flow to
finance
which is a white hole for the
workings of modern economy
so it doesn't so it works
so that really doesn't give us the
challenge as a value investor a true
value investor
you just have to really reframe
yourself from betting too often
knowing that the financial market
doesn't really work too well but a lot
of the time it works reasonably well
and so you want to really wait for the
extreme situation before you can really
make a bet
so that you have a level of margin of
safety
and b
that you can actually stand
against the whole market that do happen
that requires an extreme discipline
of
of demanding a large amount of margin of
safety
virtually all the successful
value investor practitioners really have
all that
element in common they do not bed often
and whenever they bet they require a
large large amount of marginal safety
so that they will be comfortable in case
the market works against them
and so that they are seizing the
opportunities that almost no-brainer
and that really is the most difficult
challenges
most of people really has uh
do not really have the necessary
discipline mental discipline to do that
and so you would have saved any
in the bull market everybody practice
everybody used to call themselves
investors
they buy something they think there is a
20 discount to what they think is an
intrinsic value
uh
and and
when this goes up and they really trump
themselves as a successful intelligent
and valid in the investor but then when
the market would be against them which
is very easy
twenty percent of discount is almost
within the error margin and they're
right
if the market began to and you would
have said it would be the first one
respect the market runs
that's typically the case
and so when you see a situation like
that that is usually a sign that's not
true
that is as it's properly practiced so as
a young student a young analyst or
somebody who's interested in finance
i would strongly encourage you the best
way to do that is to study
successful practices in real life and
examples or history
studied very well all the examples of
great
value investing decisions
i was talking to eisner on the way from
the airport to pick me up so we talked
about
his favorite stocking russian oil which
reminds me one of those
green examples of valiant investing back
in the early 90s
as some of you might know in the early
90s a russian but through a shock
therapy
and went into
a free market almost overnight in short
period of time they privatized some of
the most surprised
finance state assets including local oil
gas problems to talk about and
it was so short
that most people don't really understand
what it's all about
a lot of the people who work in the
companies and also other citizens will
give a certificate
about their that can really convert it
to stock ownership but most people
really don't know what it is so anybody
will come along offer them a real cash
which they recognize they were just
afraid to give it away
so as a result of the certificate
at one point it was retreating as an
extraordinarily low prices
how low is the prices
forget about the earnings
just to sort of the asset on the balance
sheet
at the time the oil prices i think in
the
four or five year average around twenty
dollars
and the reserve represented by the
balance sheet partial basis value the
per value of the oil per barrel of the
proven reserve at a really low prices as
do you remember what was the price
anybody remember
it was 20 dollars
per barrel traded on the open market
anybody can imagine how low they built
one cents
on the dollar sometimes
half says on the dollar in other words
about 10 cents to 20 cents per proven
barrier of oil on the balance sheet
and that's not even counting the
earnings
from the company this is how low it went
it was ridiculous
now i thought at that point that's some
kind of a margin of safety
even consider
uh the political situation in russia and
it ultimately traded up you know for the
longest period of time it was a 20 30
cents 50 cents
briefly traded to three dollars
and then a few years later the asian
financial crisis
occurred and russia devalued the
currencies all of a sudden that two
dollar oil no longer looks very
protected because the currents are
literally one point it went down ninety
percent i mean nine zero
but if you really bought it in the ten
cents which is a half cents half percent
of the value
less than you know now the 10 the value
turns it down 90 you still came out
quite all right
in fact you still probably made it 10
times your money
that's how an extreme situation can
become that will be a good example to
study
so you can really withstand a situation
external shock that really shocked that
one of the measure of value in this case
currency by 90 you still came up on top
that is how extreme it is that concept
will mark your safety when you do
practice
take another example a few years
afterwards
back in 97 98
the oil
open market worldwide it traded below
ten dollars
for a period of the several months
at the time
the five-year averages are probably
twenty years
as i said before
but
also the majority actually if not all of
the productions on the west is above ten
dollars cost
exxon mobil you know
you name it everything outside
uh saudi arabia couple
gulf state countries a little part of
russia part of those a small
portion it's not that small but it's
still a fraction of the overall
production
everybody's become
unprofitable at ten dollars per hour
and at the time we have not really
figured out uh
how to replace voting
and so
there were plenty plenty companies at
the
uh time not losing money even at
attendance
and who's really making a great and who
has a huge amount of on the balance
sheet
and you can calculate
as to what it is about you per
share and so there are really examples
of examples of the examples so in every
period of time as i was in business this
is from the mid 90s
90s 94
95 so it's nearly 20 years
i've never really uh
go through a period of time that i
couldn't really find something just
enticing and interesting
so if you especially operate a smaller
pool of the money at any time
because you're really kind of choosing
from 100 000
different
securities mostly stocks all over the
world
there are always opportunities like that
that give you plenty of margin of safety
but of course the most interesting thing
you want to do
is not only to talk about the asset
you're talking about enduring burning
generating franchise a compounding
machine in other words
if you can combine the cheap prices on
the asset there's also the quality of
the asset the ability to consistently
generate cash
earnings on a compound and growing basis
that is the holy grail that you can
really hold for longest period of time
and no matter what
the market is really for against you you
can really basically ignore it
now does a situation like that exist
i would argue it does
maybe not for the larger amount of
capital the smaller cap amount of the
capital if i were a student today
and it has a few tens of thousands of
dollars i'll be really very happy to
live in the environment as it is today
now if i have a larger amount of money
we have multiple challenges all over the
world
which we cannot really go into today but
if you have a smaller pool of money
there are tremendous opportunities like
that in all small pockets
i give you one uh an example that you
can really do more work to see whether
it's interesting
in career
there's a
form of a securities how to prefer
securities essentially it is a
non-voting comment stock
that
pays slightly more preferred dividend
not much
but it cannot vote
but for
interesting reasons
that they are trading sometimes up to 70
80 discount
to their common equipment
and in that group of securities there
are several companies that really have
enduring franchise
that have been growing
earnings and revenue on a compounded
basis
for over three or four decades
because the franchise is nearly as a
fortress with uh
purchase life
great earning power machines that still
have a lot of opportunity of expansion
and trading at uh
prices that uh is essentially just tiny
fraction of what really should be
worth in an open and a private
transaction if you buy the whole company
in fact you have really a comparison
of the common stock in a voting common
stock equivalent
a situation just like that really exists
even today
there's absolutely no reason especially
some of those companies that i talk
about it
the family really controls the voting of
the common anyway
so there is virtually no differences
between the common the voting common and
non-voting time there was virtually no
no differences
and yet the training was eighty percent
uh disco i'm not talking about twenty
percent this time eighty percent discuss
trading the twenty cents on the dollar
if you believe that that common language
is like the truth true value
so the opportunity that my point is
really existed on all the different ones
so if you're starting your career if
you're young if i were you starting all
over again
i would have first to study
all the grading examples in the past
in which the market went to the extreme
on a small segment until the security
that gives you a tremendous tremendous
margin of safety
now all sorts of things happen and you
are still come out okay
even if you lose money you're still in
the game
study that one and then study what is
available today
at any given time there are always
always opportunities like that
it really has something to do with our
fundamental human psychology
as long as human remains the same which
i suspected will after billions of years
that opportunity exists
which is quite an encouraging sign for
young people so if i were you i would
have been very excited today as i was
when i was sitting in the audience in
your shoe
about
20 years ago
so good luck for that i'll open for
questions
[Applause]
yeah i have a question now
when do we just how do you decide when
you sell this stuff
well it's a very interesting question
now
it depends what's the source of your
value
is some of the example that i stated the
source of the value it really is the is
the asset value
and in that case you really
want to really re-evaluate your
scenarios up
side and downside
every once in a while because the
situation changes for example in your
favorite stock and the russian oil the
local oils
and gas problems i sold it two years
after i first bought it
[Music]
and they just other but at the time
there's still kind of a treating
probably 90 percent
80 to 90 percent discount but i think
the 80 90 discount is warranted somehow
today it is still trading at a huge
discount i don't know what it is you're
probably more updated than i do
but relative to all the other countries
that i would feel less comfortable
with that discount i mean more
and it just happened to be given a 99
just come 99.9
percent discount that was that was a
fluke
now if you're really talking about
earnings
i tend to be less uh in a hurry
because if you really bet it right
the earning will continue to grow
and every time you sell stock you
basically take out
essentially a 30 to 40 percent
of of interest-free borrow
by not really selling the stock you
avoided paying the capital gain taxes
uh the state of federal together is
somewhere in 20 30 to 40 i think it's
going up
as long as you're in that in a sense
you're borrowing from the government on
the interest-free and risk-free basis
and if the asset
underlying
asset continue to grow on a compounded
basis
i would say
that is reason to be less in hurry to
sell
if it reflects in the uh fair value i
would
uh keep it but if they really go through
the extreme overvalue situations and the
business environment changes
of course you change your course of
action and that's a good thing about uh
investing everything related
and affected investment
all the circumstances changes all the
time that's why the game is so fun
yeah hi
i was wondering what is the margin of
safety that you look for before you
decided to buy
yeah again that has something to do with
the quality of the asset if you're
buying
if the quality of the asset is very high
your demand on asset basis is a low
because you are
uh you are demanding that a margin of
safety on the upside in terms of the
earning generating power
whatever it is you have to have an
insight as to what this asset can
generate for you
and somehow it is somewhat of a
difference inside a unique insight
whether you know the business
particularly better than anybody else's
if you really buy into the future
earnings
or the asset for whatever reason you can
withstand the balance sheet better
than the other people you have to have a
better insight as to what is the
appropriate value and therefore it may
not really appear to other people as
enlarged enough of a margin in your mind
you have a very very large margin safety
in my own case i just think that the
larger you can get it the better
you want to have a very very large
safety right right so how about assuming
that you have no insights whatsoever as
to what the
future earnings power is and you just
assume that it's a no growth business
what would you pay for that business
well in the case of the russians since i
know very little about russian i have
every reason to be suspect suspicious
so that goes to 99
and i get extremely uncomfortable when
it goes to eighty percent for example
and in the end and actually that ninety
percent evaporated because of the
currency changes although they came back
uh so each situation is different but in
in in the environment i understand the
external forces i understand the
management i understand the general
business practice in that particular
culture you would probably you know 70
80 is actually pretty good
it's all a situation specific
okay i just have to say that that's a
pretty high hurdle rate
well that's why you don't have to my
whole point is you don't have to swing a
lot
one of the key of a success for
being a long-term successful investor is
you have to endure a long period of time
in which you do nothing
you don't have to do a lot in order to
be fabulously rich and prosperous
that's the good thing about to this game
you study all the time but you don't
have to do anything
and every time you do when you don't
have enough market of safety you can
come out to really
lose
and that's the really
much worse thing than really
than doing nothing but every time you do
do something
if you have large enough of a margin of
safety
your upside has also become huge and
then there are many many examples and i
wouldn't have time to go into it
and in which when you turn it when you
turn out to be right
the upside is just enormous you could
really surprise your wildest dreams
and you want to wait for those fat
pitches most of the time okay and then
lastly how much cash are you holding now
that is different from time to time it
depends on the
hi i'm opportunity from berkeley um i'm
curious to share your opinion on what
you think are the domestic industry
segments you think are most overvalued
and undervalued today
well i i
you know
there is as i said that
to be a successful investor you don't
really have to know everything
you don't have to be a
who claims he knows everything every
stock
uh
in fact that if you truly know something
that
you fall into a small circle
uh buffett would like to the manga would
like to call a circle of confidence you
want to find in your circle that circle
tends to be small
so every time you hear people talking
about oh gee i think that industry is
over this industry
is is undervalued
i
that is not intellectually honest to me
at least
investing the last thing you want is to
have that error of error
you know arrogance might be a too strong
word but
i think the more honest you are
intellectually the more prosperous you
tend to me
i have never failed any intellectually
inherited people who can successfully
practice the game of the investment
first of all thank you for coming
you talk about finding you know great
financial dislocations to try and find
these tremendous upside situations
would you maybe expound on your
research like how do you find these
these great dislocations where things
are trading in ten percent of what they
were
well
i i find as i liked it in my own career
of all the ideas that i find they really
tend to come from
all sources
i don't have a particular rule where
they come from
if you
have a curious mind if you study all the
time you maintain a good network of
relationships with other smart
intelligent investors that have a way of
really looking at what they do
you tend to find a lot of us first of
all interesting ideas
and in today's age
because
this regular requirement was disclosure
i wouldn't be surprised you can really
find a lot of great ideas
uh just out of reading publicly
available information it is judging what
is a good opportunity
that is really difficult
what's the process like have you uh
finally developed a conviction an idea
is that kind of like an aha moment or do
you describe how you come to that
conviction level well one of my favorite
way to describe the uh
conviction of idea is
that if you can find the most
intelligent person who would oppose your
idea
and you're able to argue more
successfully than he does against your
idea that is when you can develop or
entitle to some views
and even then you want to really confine
yourself to a small segment
of things that you think you're right
of course as you
gain more experiences your circle tends
to expand
but only small and gradually
over time
so i think of being intellectually
honest is a huge requirement for being a
successful analyst and a successful
investor
yes sir thank you for coming today i uh
wanted to ask you a question about
portfolio construction and
uh just hear your comments on
diversification in the last session
there was a lot of discussion about
diversification and the importance of it
um my sense is that you're more of a
concentrated investor some other
investors are like that where where does
that what kind of role does
diversification play or how do you think
of it in building a portfolio
well you always have to have some kind
of a
diversification
uh
because a you could be wrong and b even
if you're right
you're betting on statistics
in other words the future is essentially
a distribution of all probabilities
so
let's see you have a 90
conviction
and you're right
that event is 90 but then 10 chances
happen
and so you don't want to that 10
to get you out of the game
so you do need to diversification
on the other hand
that
recognizing
uh
is extremely rare to find no-brainer
great opportunities extremely rare
in fact you have to wait for a long time
for the fat fish to come to you
so when that happens
you certainly do not want to diversify
away the opportunity that you have been
waiting patiently for a long time to
discover for some really inferior other
opportunities
the investment is essentially is the
opportunity cost
so one other
alternative have to really just by
itself by comparing it with the one you
already have
and so when you make that comparison you
tend not to really diversify too much
you want to find it feel
very very good ones that have a very
high
uh conviction that might arise
and so yes you you do a little bit both
so in that example and you're kind of
hitting precisely what i'm getting at
in a very high conviction idea
what do you feel the the limits are in
terms of you know how much you could be
invested and what you know what
considerations do you have
well i would say as i said that all
decisions ought to be able to through
the concept of the opportunity cost is
what else can i do with the cash i have
and cash by the way
is a really a fundamentally important
asset and if i don't really find
anything else or if i find a bunch of
other opportunity fear into cash
then i would have given him cash
and so
i i would say that
that i
i it never bothers me you know with a
large amount of cash i can't find a
great opportunities
at the same time when i find say one
good ideas i'll let it
get
a little bigger percentage of the
of the
of the portfolio and then everything
else will compare with what i already
have which is cash
and sometimes holding cash can be the
result of a bottom-up research
i always believe that's the case
okay well thank you very much
[Applause]